Guide to the Irvin Goodman papers 1927-1958.
Oregon Historical Society Davies Family Research Library
Irvin Goodman papers
1927-1958
Oregon Historical Society, Davies Family Research Library
Mss 1811
Goodman, Irvin, 1897-1958.
3.6 cubic feet 1 document case and 10 flat boxes
Collection includes: Speeches, papers, reminiscences and notes on the judicial system, civil rights, espionage, discrimination and class conflict; Correspondence, 1950-1959, regarding speaking engagements, writing projects, etc.; Newspaper clippings and scrapbooks regarding his cases, including the Nicolai Redin spy case and many murder cases. Irvin Goodman (1897-1958) was a Portland, Oregon native and was admitted to the Oregon Bar in 1924.
Irvin Goodman (1897-1958) was a Portland, Oregon native and was admitted to the Oregon Bar in 1924. He became a well-known and successful defense attorney, working on such cases as those of Nicolai Gregorovich Redin, and Wayne and Sherry Fong. He died from a heart ailment in 1958.
Collection includes: Speeches, papers, reminiscences and notes on the judicial system, civil rights, espionage, discrimination and class conflict; Correspondence, 1950-1959, regarding speaking engagements, writing projects, etc.; Newspaper clippings and scrapbooks regarding his cases, including the Nicolai Redin spy case and many murder cases.
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series A: Comments and speechs
Series B: Manuscripts
Series C: Other loose materials
Series D: Scrapbooks
Gift of Ora Goodman, January 1987, Lib. Acc. 18064.
This collection is open to the public.
Irvin Goodman family collection, Accession 25801, Oregon Historical Society Research Library,Portland, Or.
Additional materials relating to the Goodman family are held at the Oregon Jewish Museum and Center for Holocaust Education, Portland, Oregon.
Goodman, Irvin, -- 1897-1958 -- Archives.
Civil rights -- Law and legislation -- Oregon -- Portland.
Espionage.
Justice, Administration of -- Oregon -- Portland.
Lawyers -- Oregon -- Portland.
Murder -- Oregon -- Portland.
Clippings (information artifacts
Correspondence.
Scrapbooks.
Speeches (documents)
Reminiscences.
Oregon
- Comments and speeches, 1931-1948; Series A (Box-folder 1/1-1/5)
  Topics include criminal syndicalism, trade unionism, legal justice, civil liberities, civil rights, parole and probation, deportation issues, and the Fifth Amendment.
- Manuscripts, circa 1940-1946; Series B
  - "The Redin Spy Story", circa 1946 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - "They Were Called 'Reds'", circa 1940 (Box-folder 1/7)
- Other loose materials, 1933-1958; Series C
  - Biographical sketch and appreciative letters (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Correspondence re Testimonial Dinner, 1949 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1958 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Articles by and/or about Goodman, 1935-1958 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - News clippings, 1933-1939 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Certificate awarded by Civil Rights Congress of Oregon, 1949 June 3 (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Pencil sketch of Irvin Goodman (Box-folder 5/2)
- Scrapbooks, 1927-1958; Series D
  - Ray Becker and Centralia case, 1935-1958 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Harry Bridges case, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Callicote case; civil rights and liberties, 1932-1937 (Box-folder 10/1)
  - John Caughlin case, 1948 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Civil rights cases, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Deportation cases, circa 1949-1952 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Jerry Dodele case, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Julia Eaton case, 1948 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Sherry Fong case, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 6/1-6/2)
  - Wardell Henderson case, 1948 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Laura Law case, 1940 (Box-folder 5/3)
  - List of speaking engagements, etc., 1927-1931 (Box-folder 11/1)
  - List of speaking engagements; Communists, 1931-1933 (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Metaline miners case, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Nicolai Gregorovich Redin case, 1946 (Box-folder 4/1-4/3)
  - "Reds" case, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Turman and Utah Wilson case, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 2/1-2/2; 3/1-3/2)
  - Various news clippings, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 9/2)